<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on WAZIUP e.V</title>
    <link>https://waziup.org/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on WAZIUP e.V</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 22:08:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://waziup.org/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>WAZIUP AT THE BRIDGING THE STANDARDIZATION GAP SESSION ON IOT IN CAIRO</title>
      <link>https://waziup.org/news/standardization-gap-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 22:08:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waziup.org/news/standardization-gap-session/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The International Telecommunication Union (ITU) (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itu.int/&#34;&gt;https://www.itu.int/&lt;/a&gt;) organized a workshop on the thematic: &amp;ldquo;Bridging the Standardization Gap (BSG): Session on IoT&amp;rdquo; in Cairo (Egypt) on May 6th 2018 (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itu.int/en/ITU-T/Workshops-and-Seminars/bsg/20180506/Pages/default.aspx&#34;&gt;https://www.itu.int/en/ITU-T/Workshops-and-Seminars/bsg/20180506/Pages/default.aspx&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short training course on rapid protototyping with ACEIoT</title>
      <link>https://waziup.org/news/training-with-aceiot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 05:35:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waziup.org/news/training-with-aceiot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WAZIUP organized a short course on IoT rapid application prototyping course in Rwanda in cooperation with ACEIoT (African Center of Excellence in Internet of Things).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WAZIHack 2017 at ISpace</title>
      <link>https://waziup.org/news/wazihack-2017-at-ispace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 21:33:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waziup.org/news/wazihack-2017-at-ispace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From the 20th February to 22nd February 2018 two agricultural capacity building organisations ; AG-STUD Africa Boot Camp and AgriHouse Foundation, in partnership with iSpace Foundation organised the first WAZIHACK in Ghana.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WAZIUP at IoT Tunisia</title>
      <link>https://waziup.org/news/wazup-at-iot-tunisia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 10:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waziup.org/news/wazup-at-iot-tunisia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WAZIUP presented at the annual IoT Tunisia 2018 Workshop and Forum that took place on 26th and 27th April&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IoT Applications Training</title>
      <link>https://waziup.org/news/iot-applications-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 10:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waziup.org/news/iot-applications-training/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The African Center of Excellence in the Internet of Things (ACEIoT) in collaboration with WAZIUP is organizing a short course in Rapid Prototyping for IoT. This hands-on activity will focus on building open, low-cost, sustainable IoT solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WAZIUP Application Platform Version 2</title>
      <link>https://waziup.org/news/platform-version2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 10:44:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waziup.org/news/platform-version2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The new version of WAZIUP IoT application platform is released. Let us guide you through the making of full IoT solutions from the sensor to applications: you will build your own IoT LoRa sensing platform and your own web application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WAZIUP &#43; Loranga</title>
      <link>https://waziup.org/news/waziup&#43;loranga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 10:24:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waziup.org/news/waziup&#43;loranga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are proud to announce you that we have a partnership with LA FÁBRICA ALEGRE to give WAZIUP one (1) Loranga board for every 10 boards sold (when they reach the campaign goal). WAZIUP can then give these boards to some selected African organizations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Spin Off</title>
      <link>https://waziup.org/news/business-spin-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 09:19:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waziup.org/news/business-spin-off/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wazihacks  #4  and #5 were organised by our partners from UGB (Senegal) and Ispace (Ghana) in late 2017 and early 2018. It was as usual a good occasion to gather developers and proceed to a buisiness spin off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WAZIUP in Cameroon</title>
      <link>https://waziup.org/news/ensa-safi-morocco/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 09:54:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waziup.org/news/ensa-safi-morocco/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The IRD (Institut de recherche pour le développement) is a French research organism that emphasizes on interdisciplinarity research. The IRD has focused its research for over 65 years on the relationship between man and its environment, in Africa, Mediterranean, Latin America, Asia and the French tropical overseas territories. UMMISCO is the IRD&amp;rsquo;s international laboratory on complex system modelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WAZIUP Presensation at ENSA Safi Morocco</title>
      <link>https://waziup.org/news/waziup-in-morocco/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 09:12:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waziup.org/news/waziup-in-morocco/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ecole Nationale des Sciences Appliquées (ENSA) at Safi, Morocco and the IRD/UMMISCO at Yaoundé, Cameroon, have recently expressed great interest in the low-cost and open IoT approach promoted by the EU H2020 WAZIUP project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WAZIUP in Malaysia</title>
      <link>https://waziup.org/news/suts-cdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 08:53:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waziup.org/news/suts-cdf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At  Swinburne   Sarawak,    in  addition    to  presenting  the WAZIUP  technology  to  CDF&amp;rsquo;s   researchers,    a   workshop    on  the applications    of  Internet    of  Things  (IoT)   for government  officials   was organized   on  7   February    2018    by  Director    of  CDF,    Prof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WAZIUP in Vietnam</title>
      <link>https://waziup.org/news/waziup-hcmut/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 08:53:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waziup.org/news/waziup-hcmut/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The IoT Lab at Ho Chi Minh University of Technology (HCMUT, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam) and the  Centre  for Digital Futures (CDF) at Swinburne University   of  Technology  Sarawak Campus  (SUTS,  Kuching, Malaysia) have recently expressed  great   interest in the low-cost and open IoT approach promoted by  the EU  H2020 WAZIUP project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WAZIUP in Bangladesh</title>
      <link>https://waziup.org/news/waziup-in-bangladesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 17:22:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waziup.org/news/waziup-in-bangladesh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr.-Ing. Abdur Rahim (project coordinator) of WAZIUP organized a seminar on IoT and Big Data for Sustainable Development at EAST WEST University (EWU) of Bangladesh on 23rd January 2018. The students and staff from universities participated in the Seminar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UGB Workshop</title>
      <link>https://waziup.org/news/ugb-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 00:08:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waziup.org/news/ugb-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the wake of the physical meetings, UGB (Université Gaston Berger) of Saint Louis ( Sénégal) organized a workshop that gathered professionals and teachers in several areas such as agriculture, water, mathematics, and so on. The objective was to point out the problematics in those areas of competency and present how Waziup platform and  IoT solution  could  face issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wazihack Senegal 2017</title>
      <link>https://waziup.org/news/wazihack-senegal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 15:40:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waziup.org/news/wazihack-senegal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wazihack has been organized with the collaboration of the UGB incubator, in St Louis, Senegal. During the Wazihack call for proposals, more than 30 teams submitted their projects from all over the country. However, 10 proposals regarding IoT, and innovative aspects were selected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IoT Clubs in Benin and Côte d’Ivoire</title>
      <link>https://waziup.org/news/iot-clubs-in-benin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waziup.org/news/iot-clubs-in-benin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IoT Clubs are original initiative to tackle the process of spreading IoT in Africa.  They are based  on  the FabLabs networks to localize the european project WAZIUP. Then  the clubs become the lieu  for sensibilisation and experimentation on the issues and potential of IoT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WAZIHack Togo 2017</title>
      <link>https://waziup.org/news/wazihack-togo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 14:59:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waziup.org/news/wazihack-togo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WAZIHACK Togo took place in the capital of Togo, Lome in February 2017. The event lasted three days from 17th to 21th February 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WAZIHack Ghana 2017</title>
      <link>https://waziup.org/news/wazihack-ghana/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2017 15:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waziup.org/news/wazihack-ghana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This event took place in iSpace the 24-25 February 2017.
In Ghana, the participants were not very familiar with the Arduinos and LoRa. The format was modified and turned into an Introduction to IoT, the sample sensors, how to assemble the devices, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Low-Cost Long-Range IoT Gateway</title>
      <link>https://waziup.org/news/build-waziup-gateway/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 16:05:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waziup.org/news/build-waziup-gateway/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you want to know exactly and in a simple and visual way how to build your low-cost long-range IoT Gateway with Lora?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UGB Gateway</title>
      <link>https://waziup.org/news/ugb-gateway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 16:23:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waziup.org/news/ugb-gateway/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WAZIUP partner UGB (Gaston Berger University) mounted 3 gateways and 3 end devices with temperature and humidity output. They have been placed on the roof of the IT computing center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IoT Big Data 2016</title>
      <link>https://waziup.org/news/iot-big-data-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 17:01:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waziup.org/news/iot-big-data-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Charlotte Dupont, EGM data scientist, and Sabrine Fatnassi, EGM test &amp;amp; validation engineer, presented a poster at IotBigData 2016 in Roma, Italy. The poster showed an overview of the project, with both IoT andBigData Platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The consortium visits two fish farms in Ghana</title>
      <link>https://waziup.org/news/fish-farm-visit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 16:57:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waziup.org/news/fish-farm-visit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WAZIUP partners visited two different real-life testing scenarios that will be used to effectively integrate the real world fish farming situations/solutions with the digital world of WAZIUP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop in Ghana</title>
      <link>https://waziup.org/news/workshop-in-ghana/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 16:42:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waziup.org/news/workshop-in-ghana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The second physical meeting between WAZIUP consortium members occurred in Accra, Ghana lasting 2 days. It culminated with a public presentation event for the developer community in Accra to learn about the platform, a hands on demonstration, meet the WAZIUP partners, learn about the program and present the evolution of tasks achieved to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WAZIUP First Milestones</title>
      <link>https://waziup.org/news/waziup-milestones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 16:36:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waziup.org/news/waziup-milestones/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WAZIUP has been evolving since its launch in February 2016. The coordination consortium is progressively making the first steps towards the accomplishment of the objectives targeted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IoT Week 2016</title>
      <link>https://waziup.org/news/iot-week-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 17:08:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waziup.org/news/iot-week-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The IoT week was this year held in Belgrade on 31st May to 2nd June and attracted about 400 participants from 30 countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>